Guide to the Cedric J. Robinson and Elizabeth P. Robinson Collection on Third World News Review TAM.835
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Third World News Review Episodes, 1981-2015; 1.67 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and a cassette box; 1.79 Terabytes in 496 computer files; 3 U-matic; 15 VHS; 29 audiocassettes
  - October 22, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_178
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include Benazir Bhutto's return to Pakistan and the explosion of two bombs during her return parade in Karachi; rising gasoline prices; American opposition to a Russian gas pipeline proposal for Europe; criticism of new DNA testing mandate by French government on immigrants; the upcoming general election and rise of extreme right-wing party in Switzerland; and the death of South African reggae musician Lucky Debe.
  - October 29, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_179
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the meeting of Condoleezza Rice, Robert Gates, and Vladimir Putin to discuss the U.S. desire to place a missile defense system in Poland and the Czech Republic; the ChevronTexaco trial in Ecuador for environmental damages; the French pesticide problem in Martinique and Guadeloupe; and the trials of dictators at the International Criminal Court at the Hague.
  - November 5, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_180
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Thomas Jacob. Discussed topics include the election of Cristina Fernández de Kirchner as President in Argentina; Argentinian politics and the economy; controversial racial comments made by scientist James Watson and the history of Watson's career; Pakistan in a state of emergency; and the insurgency in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa.
  - November 12, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_181
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include a conference focused on the role of women in the freedom of expression and community media in North Africa and the Middle East; ecological repercussions after a major storm in Eastern Europe and the Kerch Strait; the violent police response to a peaceful protest in Tbilisi, Georgia; tensions between Turkey and Iraqi Kurds; and intensified violence in Mogadishu.
  - November 19, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_182
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include America's imposed presence in the Middle East; growing political and military instability in the Middle East; a conflict related to the Nahr al-Bared refugee camp; the creation of a unified African common post with the help of the United States; and the arrest of members from the NGO L'Arche de Zoé in Chad for allegedly abducting 103 African children.
  - November 26, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_183
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include workers protesting the re-election of Gonzalo Sánchez de Lozada as the president of Bolivia in 2002 and his status as a fugitive in the United States; attempts to return displaced Iraqis to their homes in Baghdad; an open letter from the Electronic Intifada calling for the protection of Palestinians; and the resignation of Lebanese president Emile Zahoud.
  - December 3, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_184
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the Russian parliamentary election results; the popularity of President Vladamir Putin and his control of the Russian media; a 7.4 earthquake in Martinique and the West Indies; a rebellion in a city north of Paris about the lack of employment opportunities; and the Villiers-le-Bel riots in France.
  - December 10, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_185
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include amendment changes to the Venezuelan Constitution; the cult of personality surrounding President Hugo Chávez; Iran's nuclear weapons program; Israel and the U.S. dealing in arms; and the shooting of four people in the Firestone community in response to a worker strike.
  - December 17, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_186
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include the African National Congress delegates meeting at the University of Limpopo; South African politics; a coup, Antonio Trillanes, and the Writ of Amparo passing in the Philippines; the Association of Southeast Asian Nations conference in Manila; and a climate conference in Bali.
  - January 7, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_187
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include conflicting Kenyan presidential election results; the trial of President Charles Taylor; FARC (Colombian armed forces) asking Venezuelan president President Hugo Chávez to release hostages; Italy wanting to prosecute members of Operation Condor; growing pressures to deport undocumented immigrants from France; and accusations against Israel for human rights violations in Palestine.
  - January 14, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_188
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include U.S. and international agents working for and against Kosovo's fight for independence, past bombing campaigns, and the UN and NATO's protection of Kosovo; Hashim Thaçi elected as prime minister of Kosovo; U.S. Base Camp Bondsteel; the war in Afghanistan; Sri Lanka and the Tamil Tigers militant group; and the assassination of Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto.
  - January 28, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_189
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include a meeting between Russia and the U.S. to discuss missile defense systems; Iran's nuclear weapon capabilities; President George W. Bush's speech on Cuba and how it relates to Bulgaria; the ChevronTexaco trial in Ecuador; an ecological disaster in Guadeloupe; and the International Court of Justice announcing the indictments of several African dictators.
  - February 4, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_190
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Cedric Robinson and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include continuing conflicts over the Kenyan presidential election and dissent towards the Kibaki government; protests in France about undocumented peoples and increased undocumented immigration; the abduction of children from Chad, the Chadian Civil War, and French military involvement with the war; and the Iraq War.
  - February 11, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_191
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the elections in Serbia and election of Boris Tadić as president; anticipation of Kosovo's independence; investigation of possible anti-immigrant arson in Germany; growing Islamophobia and xenophobia in Europe; the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine over Gaza; elections in Chad; and the movement of refugees between Chad and the Sudan and the impact of French troops in the region.
  - February 25, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_192
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Fidel Castro's resignation as president of Cuba, a history of the Cuban revolution, and Castro's legacy; Cuban politics in relation to race; LGBTQIA+ rights globally; HIV/AIDS; Marcus Bleasdale's book on post-colonial conflicts in the Congo; Palestinian protests at the Gaza-Israel border; and the British Labor Party deleting information from reports regarding Israel.
  - March 3, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_193
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include censorship of the Israeli press; ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine in Gaza; the Iraq War; the Argentine economic crisis since 2005; the arrests of cardboard collectors in Buenos Aires by mayor Mauricio Macri and resulting protests; a Colombian raid into Ecuador in March 2008 resulting in the death of Raúl Reyes and other FARC members; and U.S. policies in Latin America and the "War on Drugs."
  - March 10, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_194
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guest was Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the the Iraq War and anti-war sentiments globally; Iranian president Mahmoud Ahmadinejad's visit to Iraq; Kenya negotiating its power and Kofi Annan's formulation of a coalition government; Kenyan president Mwai Kibaki's history of corruption; the history of colonialism in Guinea-Bissau; and the trial of President Charles Taylor at the Hague.
  - March 17, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_195
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Enita David (Middle East) and Ghazela Rafiq (Pakistan). Discussed topics include the founding of Pakistan as secular state and post-1977 "Islamization"; former president Pervez Musharraf and U.S. interests in Pakistan; opinions on Pakistani fundamentalism and U.S. policy; the Iraq War; and the murder of Archbishop Paulos Faraj Rahho and ongoing bombings of churches in Iraq.
  - March 24, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_196
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guest was Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the testimony of Joseph "Zigzag" Marzah against President Charles Taylor at the Hague; political formation and conflict in Liberia; the Firestone rubber plantations and labor violations in Liberia; the attempted arrests of 115 undocumented migrants in France; conflicts between Chad and the Sudan; the signing of a ceasefire agreement at the Abeche Peace Talks; and a controversy surrounding the Bishop of Zimbabwe, Nolbert Kunonga.
  - March 31, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_197
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include the Iraq War; Condoleezza Rice's attempts to broker a peace agreement between Israel and Palestine; the death of Dith Pran, Cambodian Holocaust survivor and photojournalist; illness of former Filipina president Corazon Aquino; and the elections in Zimbabwe.
  - April 7, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_198
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Corey Dubin and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the Colombian free trade agreement, NAFTA, and U.S. foreign policy in Latin America; protests in France against President Nicolas Sarkozy's anti-immigration and xenophobic policies; the L'Arche de Zoé controversy in Chad; food riots in Haiti; and the election in Zimbabwe and its contested results.
  - April 14, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_199
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the assassination of two journalists in Mexico and increased media censorship there; allegations against the U.S. regarding human rights violations in the treatment of prisoners; an Islamophobic ad published in a UCSB student newspaper; protests and counter protests for Free Tibet on the UCSB campus; the commander of Lord's Resistance Army, Joseph Kony, murdering his deputy commander in Uganda; and Kenyan president Mwai Kibaki announcing his new cabinet.
  - April 21, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_200
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the death of Aimé Césaire; the concept and movement of Négritude; elections in Nepal and the success of Maoist Party; and the formation of coalition government in Pakistan and U.S. demands of Pakistan.
  - April 28, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_201
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include negotiations between Hamas, Egypt, and Israel; the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine; American claims that Syria is building a nuclear reactor; the refugee crisis in the Central African Republic and Chad, as well as civil wars in that region; a proposed Colombian trade deal; human rights violations and disappearances in Colombia; and a lawsuit against United Fruit Company (Chiquita).
  - May 5, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_202
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the growing price of oil; a movement for the emancipation of the Niger Delta (MEND); political instability in Nigeria; Zimbabwe elections and the re-election of President Robert Mugabe; Liberian elections; the Tuareg rebellion in Niger; President Nicolas Sarkozy and human rights issues in Tunisia; the ambassador of France recognizing French atrocities committed in Algeria; and the history of the French Student Demonstrations of May 1968.
  - May 12, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_203
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ghazela Rafiq (Pakistan) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the U.S. Supreme Court ruling it cannot get involved with South African lawsuits against U.S. companies involved with Apartheid; Halliburton and KBR being investigated by the U.S. for the bribery of Nigerian officials; fighting in Lebanon and declarations of war from Hezbollah; reflections on a three-part al-Jazeera multi-media piece '60 Years of Division' and the current conditions in Gaza; political, social, and economic instability in Pakistan; and the Muttahida Qaumi Movement in Pakistan.
  - June 2, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_204
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the use of cluster munitions in military conflicts globally; the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine in Gaza; Desmond Tutu heading the UN investigation of Beit Hanoun killings; an attack against the indigenous peoples in Bolivia at an independence ceremony; and Mengistu Haile Mariam sentenced to death for mass murder.
  - June 9, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_205
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include fighting in the Congo's borderlands with Rwanda; anti-US beef protests in South Korea; a proposed bill in the Philippines that would require all cell phones to be registered with a fee; the death of Crispin Beltran; Israel's hint at a potential attack against Iran due to its alleged nuclear program; and President Barack Obama's statements about the unification of Jerusalem under Israel at the American Israel Public Affairs Committee (AIPAC).
  - June 16, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_206
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the investigation of U.S. government arrests in Guantanamo Bay; the U.S.-Ethiopian invasion of Somalia; human trafficking problems in Africa; the Ugandan Army trying to negotiate peace with Lord's Resistance Army; the Iraq War and subsequent refugee crisis; calls for President George W. Bush's impeachment; a military conflict in Chad and France's unwillingness to get involved; and French involvement in the Ivorian Civil War and upcoming elections in Ivory Coast.
  - June 23, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_207
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include election violence in Zimbabwe, Morgan Tsvangira not seeking re-election, and Robert Mugabe's refusal to relinquish his power; the MEND movement in Nigeria announcing a ceasefire and calls on the government to reciprocate; a lawsuit against Chevron Oil due to its complicity in murder and torture in Nigeria; continued violence in Uganda between Lord's Resistance Army and the government; anti-American beef import protests in South Korea; elections in South Korea; South Korea abandoning a cross-country canal plan; independence celebrations in the Philippines; and ongoing tensions between Israel and Iran.
  - June 30, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_208
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Iraq War and War in Afghanistan; U.S. escalation of covert operations in Iran; President Nelson Mandela's 90th birthday; the U.S. Congress removing the African National Congress from a list of potential terrorists; and the contentious election in Zimbabwe between President Robert Mugabe and Morgan Tsvangirai.
  - July 7, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_209
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Corey Dubin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Robert Mugabe and the elections in Zimbabwe; the G8 Summit in Japan; Operation Jaque in Colombia and the history of the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC); drug trafficking in Latin America; the anniversary of the International Court condemning Israel's West Bank wall; and the Iraq War.
  - July 14, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_210
    The moderator of the episode was Gerard Pigeon and the guests were Gary Colmenar and H.L.T (HQ) Quan (Asia). Discussed topics include the G8 Summit in Japan; global food crises; American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) service workers strike at UCSB campus; issues surrounding the importation of U.S. beef to Korea; Liancourt Rocks dispute between Japan and Korea; and President Nicolas Sarkozy's "Mediterranean Union."
  - July 21, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_211
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ghazala Rafiq (Pakistan) and H.L.T (HQ) Quan (Asia). Discussed topics include global food crises; the Cambodian–Thai border dispute; an ASEAN meeting in Singapore; migrant workers in Asia and Southeast Asia; the Sindhi Association of North America (SANA) convention; recent elections in Pakistan; the United States' role in the insurgency in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa; and a meeting between President Robert Mugabe and Morgan Tsvangirai in Zimbabwe.
  - July 28, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_212
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guest was Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include President Barack Obama's visit to Israel, Germany, and France; the history of French colonialism in Africa and the Caribbean; the Iraq War; a strike by Asian migrant workers in Kuwait; the arrest of Hannibal Gaddafi (son of Muammar Gaddafi) in Switzerland and how the arrest created tensions between Libya and Switzerland; and the death of Egyptian filmmaker Youssef Chahine.
  - August 19, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_213
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ghazela Rafiq (Pakistan) and Corey Dubin. Discussed topics include the resignation of Pervez Musharraf, calls for his impeachment, and legacy of his policies in Pakistan; the insurgency in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa; the political crisis in Bolivia; and the evolution of politics and plurinationalism in South America.
  - August 25, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_214
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ghazela Rafiq (Pakistan) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include boats with activists sidestepping Israel's blockade of Gaza in order to provide aid; the death of Mahmoud Darwish; the growing number of street children in Pakistan; the Wah bombing in Pakistan; the insurgency in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa; controversy surrounding Asif Ali Zardari; and political conflicts in Zimbabwe.
  - September 8, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_215
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include meetings in Libya between Muammar Gaddafi and Condoleezza Rice; the trial of President Charles Taylor at the Hague; the weak Japanese economy and its competition with China over Asian markets; an upcoming vote for an anti-terrorism bill in Japan; an art exhibit memorializing people who have disappeared in the Philippines; the August Russo-Georgian War; and African immigrants rioting in Roquetas de Mar, Spain after a Senegalese man was stabbed to death.
  - September 15, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_216
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Corey Dubin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include civil and political unrest in Bolivia; plurinationalism in South America; an increase of military arms sales globally; the United States, NAFTA, and Latin America; the creation of a coalition government in Zimbabwe; calls for the resignation of Thabo Mbeki as president of South Africa; the trial of President Jacob Zuma at the Johannesburg High Court; and the Duweika Rockslide in Cairo.
  - September 22, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_217
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the resignation of Ehud Olmert as Israel's prime minster; the Islamabad Marriott Hotel bombing; the resignation of Thabo Mbeki as president of South Africa and speculation whether Jacob Zuma or Kgalema Motlanthe will succeed him; and the Rwandan government releasing a 300 page report accusing France of collusion with the Rwandan genocide.
  - September 29, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_218
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ghazela Rafiq (Pakistan) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the election of Kgalema Motlanthe as president of South Africa; talks to establish a Zimbabwe Government of National Unity; an exodus of citizens out of Somalia due to the war with Ethiopia; former Prime Minister Ehud Olmert urging Israel to withdraw from the occupied territories in the name of peace; the Damascus car bombing and Tripoli-Lebanon bombings; the assassination of Malalai Kakar; and Global Threat Perceptions Report.
  - October 6, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_219
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include Somali pirates attacking trade routes; the Mitterrand–Pasqua affair, also known as "Angolagate"; the U.K. Metropolitan Black Police Association calling for a boycott due to racism; tainted milk in China and tainted rice in Japan; and smuggling tunnels in the Gaza Strip supplying food and other necessities to those in need.
  - October 13, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_220
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Corey Dubin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the election of Kgalema Motlanthe as president of South Africa; the African National Congress starting to fragment; President Thabo Mbeki's legacy in South Africa; growing tensions between the Democratic Republic of the Congo and Rwanda; the U.S. surrendering the power to appoint a World Bank president; growing labor camps in Dubai; the Peru oil scandal and resignation of most of the government; and the Council of South American Defense and Union of South American Nations (UNASUR).
  - November 3, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_221
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the 2008 U.S. election; the Iraq War; the African National Congress continuing to fragment and the creation of a new unnamed party; and the Nord-Kivu conflict in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and the rise of Laurent Nkunda.
  - November 10, 2008, TW_TAM_835_ER_222